Kheel Center Exhibit Materials /4314 G
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel Center Exhibit Materials
1975-2014
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel Center
/4314 G
3.06 cubic feet
3.1 linear ft.
Graphic document genres.
8547498
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 12, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 05, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6021/001: Theodore W. Kheel Correspondence
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
8547498
- From Factories to Fields: Child Labor in the U.S. (Box 1)
  - From Factories to Fields: Child Labor in the U.S. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Photos mounted on stiff backing, quotes, pamphlets (One Hundred Days: A Story of Children without a Chance by Jean Broadhurst, The Appeal of the Children, National Child Labor Committee, A Six Years' Battle for the Working Child by Owen R. Lovejoy)
  - From Factories to Fields: Child Labor in the U.S. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- May Day Display Items -- 2013, 2014 (Box 2)
  - May Day Display Items -- 2013, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    May Day Celebration, Local 100 - ILGWU; To Fan the Flames of Discontent Songs (booklet)
  - May Day Display Items -- 2013, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    What is May Day and Why We Celebrate It (2 copies of booklets)
  - May Day Display Items -- 2013, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Sing a Labor Song; May Day 1936 (copies of a pamphlets)
  - May Day Display Items -- 2013, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Songs of the Wobblies; Songs of the People (copies of pamphlets)
  - May Day Display Items -- 2013, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Copies of various broadsides and pamphlets (some dupls) having to do with May Day
- From Factories to Fields: Child Labor in the U.S. (2 oversize photos) (Box 3)
  - Rural factory; Young girl working inside a factory (Box 3, Folder 1)
    2 photographs
- Civil Rights Exhibit, 2014 (Box 4)
  - Civil Rights Exhibit - 2014 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- ILR School History - display panels (Box 5)
- ILR School History - display panels (Box 5)
  - Caption boards for display (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Photograph of Lois Gray [display board] (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Publications 1960-61: New York State School of Industrial & Labor Relations at Cornell University [reproduction of flyer cover] [display board] (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Cornell University: New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations: General Announcement 1945-1946 [reproduction of flyer cover] [display board] (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Cornell University Announcements: Industrial and Labor Relations 1960-1961 [reproduction of flyer cover] [display board] (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - The State is Our Campus: ILR [reproduction of flyer cover] [display board] (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Signed reproduction of the Dedication Program, Ives Quadrangle [display panel] (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Photo of M.P. Catherwood [display panel] (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Photo of Theodore Kheel [display panel] (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Photo of Catherwood Library Entrance [display panel] (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Photo of students watching stenographers [display panel] (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Photo of students touring a garment factory [display board] (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Student Council News Letter - New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University - volume 6, No. 3 [reproduction] [display panel] (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Daily Sun - May 16, 1961 [reproduction] [display board] (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Articles: Chances Rise for Red-U.S. Meeting Soon; JFK to See Diefenbaker During Visit; Rusk Yields; Geneva Talks Begin Tonight; Military Officers Claim Overthrow of Korean Govt.; U.S. Jurist Claims Nazi Held Powers
- "Chronocyclograph" of a Golf Champion (Box 6)
- "Chronocyclograph" of a Golf Champion (Box 6)
- "Chronocyclograph" of a Golf Champion (Box 6)
- "Chronocyclograph" of a Golf Champion (Box 6)
- "Chronocyclograph" of a Golf Champion (Box 6)
- "Chronocyclograph" of a Golf Champion (Box 6)
  - "Chronocyclograph" of a Golf Champion - [11' 10" x 5' 11" banner] (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Kheel Center photo id # 6126PB1F4B -- [quote from banner] - The image was taken for Frank B. Gilbreth, famed early twentieth century pioneer of industrial time-and-motion studies. The chronocyclograph technique consisted of placing small lights on dynamic points of the skilled-demonstrator's body then photographing the repeated motions of the activity to be analyzed. When filmed with a timed exposure, the key motions executed in the course of repeated processes can be seen in overlapping light paths. This image is part of a collection of historical photographs that support scholarship in the early efforts to analyze and improve industrial work processes, an activity that is still fundamental today in setting manufacturing production goals and performance standards.